<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>PeakBlog</title>
    <link>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on PeakBlog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>andershurum@gmail.com (@peakbreaker)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>andershurum@gmail.com (@peakbreaker)</webMaster>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://blog.peakbreaker.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>More data manipulation with pandas</title>
        <link>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2019-03-05-dataframe-funtimes/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>andershurum@gmail.com (@peakbreaker)</author>
        <guid>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2019-03-05-dataframe-funtimes/</guid>
        <description>Data Exploration Working with data is a lot of fun. In this day and age, there is a lot of data,
but a lack of data stories. Exploring data is about uncovering the stories
that the data may hold - whether it is anomalies or powerful insights.
Beyond the basics My first post on working
with data using pandas goes into the basics of cleaning data and some core
utilities, I would recommend starting there.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Welcome to the VIP</title>
        <link>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2019-02-27-get-yourself-verified/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>andershurum@gmail.com (@peakbreaker)</author>
        <guid>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2019-02-27-get-yourself-verified/</guid>
        <description>Being Verified Computer security in essence boils down to two things:
 Authentication : How can we prove who you are? Authorization : What access do you have?  Implementing secure systems often comes down to good habits. This
is one topic where the broken window theory tends to show its symptomps.
Meaning small hacks, lazinesses and lowering of standards tend to propagate and
eventually cause the whole system to become and unmaintainable mess.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Data Cleaning with pandas</title>
        <link>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-11-22-data-cleaning-with-pandas/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>andershurum@gmail.com (@peakbreaker)</author>
        <guid>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-11-22-data-cleaning-with-pandas/</guid>
        <description>Clean data Pandas is a data library. I dont actually mean those cute bears.
This post is based on a pull from my personal notes when learning to work with
data in python with pandas (So it might not be perfect, but hey - Im trying).
These are some of the essentials tools/skills I picked up about cleaning data.
Data scientists actually spend the majority of their time wrangling and cleaning</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Scalable Documentation</title>
        <link>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-11-13-scalable-docs/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>andershurum@gmail.com (@peakbreaker)</author>
        <guid>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-11-13-scalable-docs/</guid>
        <description>Documentation In this entry, I am happy to be writing about something I have feelings
for and about. Documentation is one of those core needs in the maslow pyramid
of technology, yet far too often overlooked.
It sounds easy, right? Just write some documents on what youre doing. Wrong,
that attitude does not scale. Unmaintained documentation is worse than no
documentation, and documentation accumulates the same technical dept as code,</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Golang with the Pålgang</title>
        <link>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-09-07-golang-with-the-paal-gang/</link>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>andershurum@gmail.com (@peakbreaker)</author>
        <guid>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-09-07-golang-with-the-paal-gang/</guid>
        <description>Just a short intro to the basics of golang with Pål
This is Pål (He is the normal looking one by the window)
Pål is the superhero developer keeping the Sensario backend operational.
I have worked Pål on his right hand side since mid 2017 and have enjoyed every
second of it. We have been getting coffee together nearly every day, spoken
and learned about software engineering together and discovered the magic of Vim</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Stuck at Terminal Island</title>
        <link>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-07-29-terminal-wifi-connect/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>andershurum@gmail.com (@peakbreaker)</author>
        <guid>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-07-29-terminal-wifi-connect/</guid>
        <description>Terminals are great Being good on the terminal gives you fine grained control over a system. It is
the hallmark skill and language of the system administrator, and even if you&#39;re not
a professional sysadmin, you still have manage a system of some sort and it would help you to be
able to manage it efficiently. If you&#39;re into IT and technology in any way
it should be obvious that obtaining linux skills is pretty much always a good investment.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Web is pretty cool</title>
        <link>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-06-13-web-basics-1/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>andershurum@gmail.com (@peakbreaker)</author>
        <guid>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-06-13-web-basics-1/</guid>
        <description>You affect the world by what you browse.
 Tim Berners Lee, inventor of the web  Web is pretty cool The web is one of the main contributors to the internet revolution. If you&#39;ve ever used a browser, or computer with an internet connection the last decade, you&#39;ve probably used the web. Its quite useful and pretty cool, but how does it work? Let&#39;s take a look!
Why is the web pretty cool?</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Cooking up VR with I-chih</title>
        <link>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-05-29-cooking-vr-with-ichih/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 29 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>andershurum@gmail.com (@peakbreaker)</author>
        <guid>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-05-29-cooking-vr-with-ichih/</guid>
        <description>Just a heads up dear reader - My posts have two parts. The first part is a personal story and the second part is purely about technology and code
&amp;ndash; If youre here just for code snippets, then scroll down &amp;ndash;
This is I-chih (she is the one to the left)
She is very concerned about the environment, and rightfully so - its an important issue. We first met back in 2017 at a clothe swapping party - back then it was after I opened a grocery store in Bergen, and I really needed some pants.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>CGI for Engineers Pt. 1</title>
        <link>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-04-08-cgi-for-engineers-1/</link>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>andershurum@gmail.com (@peakbreaker)</author>
        <guid>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-04-08-cgi-for-engineers-1/</guid>
        <description>Blender is great Blender is an open source 3D computer graphics software for creating pretty much whatever you can imagine in 3D.
It is a pretty awesome piece of software, entirely free as in beer and speech, with a great amount of features for creating professional level content. In the hands of a trained person the results can be quite astonishing. Just take a look at this short film made by the blender foundation itself:</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Hello, Jekyll!</title>
        <link>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-04-07-hello-jekyll/</link>
        <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>andershurum@gmail.com (@peakbreaker)</author>
        <guid>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-04-07-hello-jekyll/</guid>
        <description>Hello, world! Thought it was about time I set up a blog. For those who don&#39;t know me:
I am Anders and I think engineering, technology and learning about interesting topics is a fun way to spend a saturday afternoon - especially if I can materialize that knowledge into something useful.
I am not going to deny that I find battery technology and software design patterns as awesome topics of discussion, that I have at some point written a program to automate my use of Tinder, and that I find Vim keybindings in Emacs is the best thing ever.</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>