<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>python on PeakBlog</title>
    <link>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/tags/python/</link>
    <description>Recent content in python on PeakBlog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <managingEditor>andershurum@gmail.com (@peakbreaker)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>andershurum@gmail.com (@peakbreaker)</webMaster>
    <copyright>&amp;copy;{year}, All Rights Reserved</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://blog.peakbreaker.com/tags/python/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    
      
      <item>
        <title>More data manipulation with pandas</title>
        <link>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2019-03-05-dataframe-funtimes/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>andershurum@gmail.com (@peakbreaker)</author>
        <guid>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2019-03-05-dataframe-funtimes/</guid>
        <description>Data Exploration Working with data is a lot of fun. In this day and age, there is a lot of data,
but a lack of data stories. Exploring data is about uncovering the stories
that the data may hold - whether it is anomalies or powerful insights.
Beyond the basics My first post on working
with data using pandas goes into the basics of cleaning data and some core
utilities, I would recommend starting there.</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Data Cleaning with pandas</title>
        <link>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-11-22-data-cleaning-with-pandas/</link>
        <pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>andershurum@gmail.com (@peakbreaker)</author>
        <guid>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-11-22-data-cleaning-with-pandas/</guid>
        <description>Clean data Pandas is a data library. I dont actually mean those cute bears.
This post is based on a pull from my personal notes when learning to work with
data in python with pandas (So it might not be perfect, but hey - Im trying).
These are some of the essentials tools/skills I picked up about cleaning data.
Data scientists actually spend the majority of their time wrangling and cleaning</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Scalable Documentation</title>
        <link>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-11-13-scalable-docs/</link>
        <pubDate>Tue, 13 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>andershurum@gmail.com (@peakbreaker)</author>
        <guid>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-11-13-scalable-docs/</guid>
        <description>Documentation In this entry, I am happy to be writing about something I have feelings
for and about. Documentation is one of those core needs in the maslow pyramid
of technology, yet far too often overlooked.
It sounds easy, right? Just write some documents on what youre doing. Wrong,
that attitude does not scale. Unmaintained documentation is worse than no
documentation, and documentation accumulates the same technical dept as code,</description>
      </item>
      
      <item>
        <title>Web is pretty cool</title>
        <link>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-06-13-web-basics-1/</link>
        <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jun 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <author>andershurum@gmail.com (@peakbreaker)</author>
        <guid>https://blog.peakbreaker.com/post/2018-06-13-web-basics-1/</guid>
        <description>You affect the world by what you browse.
 Tim Berners Lee, inventor of the web  Web is pretty cool The web is one of the main contributors to the internet revolution. If you&#39;ve ever used a browser, or computer with an internet connection the last decade, you&#39;ve probably used the web. Its quite useful and pretty cool, but how does it work? Let&#39;s take a look!
Why is the web pretty cool?</description>
      </item>
      
    
  </channel>
</rss>